<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>the Kitchen</title>
		<link>http://thekitchen.co</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 20:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
		<description>
			the Kitchen is a full-service film and design workshop where you can bring your best ideas.
		</description>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/carsgirlsandsurfing"/>
		<feedburner:info xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" uri="carsgirlsandsurfing"/>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/"/>
		
		
		<item>
			<title>Hamster Spot</title>
			<link>/work/hamster-spot</link>
			<guid>/work/hamster-spot</guid>
			<pubDate>2013-01-30 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
			<author>thekitchen.co</author>
			<description>
				
			</description>
			<content:encoded>
				<p><a href='http://uwde.org/'>United Way of Delaware</a> bought a hamster costume from Peru, and it arrived in a burlap sack. Then they called us.</p>

<p>We were a little wary of this project at first, as I tried to explain that we wouldn&#8217;t be able to make a costume behave anything like a 3D-animated character. So when it came time to write this spot, I wanted to make sure that we drew a clear line of distinction between this character and the famous ones that everyone (apparently, other than me) knows.</p>

<p>The shoot turned out to be an incredibly enjoyable experience, and we&#8217;re very happy with the final result.</p>

<p>We got a lot of help with this spot, and we need to thank them. For one, <a href='http://www.dartfirststate.com/'>DART</a> could not have been any more helpful. We weren&#8217;t sure we were going to be able to pull off our bus scenes, and even thought about shooting them guerilla-style, just board one of the Market Street Trolleys and hope no one yelled at us. We were foolish to worry. Not only was DART glad to help, but they gave us a bus and a driver for the whole morning, and on extremely short notice.</p>

<p><a href='http://parselsinc.com'>Parcels</a> provided the confetti, which was just the leftovers from the hole punching machine. Worked perfectly. If you need any of that, they&#8217;ve got garbage bags full of the stuff.</p>

<p>Steve Gold was a real trooper playing the hamster character, which we named Hamilton, and after putting on the costume for less than an hour one day, I have a renewed respect for what mascots must be going through.</p>

<p><a href='http://www.myspace.com/whirledblues'>Nate Farrar</a>, <a href='http://tomspiker.virb.com/'>Tom Spiker</a>, and <a href='http://www.myspace.com/calvinweston'>Calvin Weston</a> recorded the music for us and that amazing voice you hear belongs to <a href='http://www.voices.com/people/dmill'>David Milligan</a> of Philadelphia.</p>

<p>Also, a big shout-out to our favorite member of the Wilmington Police Department, Mike Wilkerson.</p>

<p>Now <a href='http://uwde.org/'>go make a donation already</a>.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Angelo's Luncheonette</title>
			<link>/work/angelos-luncheonette</link>
			<guid>/work/angelos-luncheonette</guid>
			<pubDate>2012-11-02 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<author>thekitchen.co</author>
			<description>
				
			</description>
			<content:encoded>
				<p>Angelo&#8217;s Luncheonette is a little place on the corner in the 40 Acres (near Trolley Square). Muzzi, the owner, has worked here for 45 years. When you walk into the place, it feels like you&#8217;ve gone back in time.</p>

<p>We decided to shoot a little video to try and capture the essence of the place. It was a great time.</p>

<p>This is one of the friendliest places you&#8217;ll ever walk into.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>10 Lessons from DCAD Students</title>
			<link>/work/dcad-lessons</link>
			<guid>/work/dcad-lessons</guid>
			<pubDate>2012-07-10 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<author>thekitchen.co</author>
			<description>
				
			</description>
			<content:encoded>
				<p>This video came up about a week and a half before <a href='http://dcad.edu'>DCAD</a> students would be leaving for the summer, so we needed a concept we could execute production on very quickly.</p>

<p>The question we asked each of the ten students we interviewed is: &#8220;What can you teach a potential incoming DCAD student in a minute or less?&#8221; After pre-screening a bunch of students, we found ourselves left with ten ideas we thought were pretty great, and we went about shooting them the following day.</p>

<p>This was our first shoot with the <a href='http://sounddevices.com/products/702/'>Sound Devices 702</a> recorder, which we used in concert with our <a href='http://www.sounddevices.com/products/302/'>Sound Devices 302</a>. If you have the means, I really recommend it.</p>

<p>Sorry for that, but they&#8217;re just (OH MY GOD) so nice.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>United Way SuperConnector</title>
			<link>/work/superconnector</link>
			<guid>/work/superconnector</guid>
			<pubDate>2012-06-21 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<author>thekitchen.co</author>
			<description>
				
			</description>
			<content:encoded>
				<p>It was fantastic working with the United Way of Delaware on this video, and the immensely talented <a href='/kitchen-logo'>Brad Wason</a> of DMG Marketing, even though we were a bit time-crunched (we put this video together, production and post-production, in less than two weeks).</p>

<p>We hit some new milestones with this video, including a full move to Final Cut X, which I will do a post about later. I&#8217;ve concluded that, though flawed, FCPX is pretty great software, and the things that make me crazy about it (hello &#8220;Share&#8221; menu&#8230;) are outweighed by great new features, some of which (sigh) did indeed come from iMovie.</p>

<p>This was also our first time using our makeshift <a href='/tools/interrotron'>Interrotron</a>, which I think had a tremendous impact on the performance of the interviewees, and adds a lot to the emotional impact of the piece.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Our Makeshift Interrotron</title>
			<link>/tools/interrotron</link>
			<guid>/tools/interrotron</guid>
			<pubDate>2012-06-20 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<author>thekitchen.co</author>
			<description>
				
			</description>
			<content:encoded>
				<p>Errol Morris is one of my favorite filmmakers. If you&#8217;ve never seen <em>The Thin Blue Line</em> or <em>The Fog of War</em> or <em>Fast, Cheap, and Out of Control</em>, you need to. His films are a unique cinematic experience, and it just so happens that the essential medium he uses to communicate, filmed interviews, is what we do all the time. (I would not compare our interviews for corporate videos to Morris&#8217;s brilliant work. It&#8217;s just a similar interaction between director, camera, and interviewee.)</p>

<p>One of the ways that Morris&#8217;s films feel so different and personal is that his subjects talk directly into the camera, creating a sense of eye contact for the audience. He accomplishes this using an invention he calls the <a href='http://www.errolmorris.com/content/eyecontact/interrotron.html'>Interrotron</a>, which is a piece of one-way glass put in front of the camera lens onto which he projects a video image of his face. This way, the interview subject can look at <em>Morris</em> (or the representation of him), and simultaneously be looking directly into the camera lens.</p>

<p>My former boss Jim Scherzi had an old teleprompter machine laying around that he hadn&#8217;t used in a while, and I asked if I could borrow it for the United Way shoot. Instead of putting words on the screen, I connected it to my Macbook and opened up Photobooth, putting my face on the screen for my interview subjects to look at as I asked them questions.</p>

<p>I was a little scared that they wouldn&#8217;t take to it (turns out <a href='http://www.errolmorris.com/content/eyecontact/interrotron.html'>Morris was scared at first too</a>), but it worked brilliantly.</p>

<p>We&#8217;re all used to seeing interviews done news-style, like a reverse shot in a narrative film where the character is talking off-camera to another character. In the case of the news, that&#8217;s Bob Costas. But in so many documentaries and certainly in the videos we make, the person we intend the interviewee to be speaking with is the audience itself.</p>

<p>To improve upon this, I&#8217;d like to get some bigger one-way glass (two pieces) and a couple of flat-panel monitors, so that both my subject and I can talk with natural eye contact. For this first trial run, I was forced to look at the iSight hole on my Macbook Air most of the time, which is a bit of an alienating experience. And then I was constantly checking my monitor which was mounted just above my screen, but still not <em>on</em> the lens itself, creating the same problem for my interviewees as the audience might have on conventionally shot interviews. The problem of distance. Lack of eye contact (the reason <a href='/eyeliner'>video chatting still sucks a whole lot more than being in person</a>).</p>

<p>So next time we do one of these, I&#8217;ll have an excuse to buy some new stuff! (and we get to build something)</p>

<p>After seeing the results, especially with the little boy Donald, who certainly could never talk directly into a camera with that kind of real, natural performance, I never want to do interviews the old way again.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Greetings, Jane Austen Nerds</title>
			<link>/work/jane-austen-day</link>
			<guid>/work/jane-austen-day</guid>
			<pubDate>2012-03-23 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<author>thekitchen.co</author>
			<description>
				
			</description>
			<content:encoded>
				<p>Sometimes you take a low-paying project from a non-profit just because it sounds like it&#8217;s going to be fun. This was one of those projects.</p>

<p>The <a href='http://www.jasnaeastpa.org/'>Jane Austen Society of North America, Eastern Pennsylvania Region</a> (not to be confused with the Jane Austen Society of North America, Western Pennsylvania Region&#8230;) wanted to put together some little 15-30 second videos to promote their big Jane Austen Day event.</p>

<p>I did not know how much Jane Austen hysteria was going on around the nation and here in our own back yard, and just to warn you, these little spots epitomize the &#8220;inside joke.&#8221;</p>

<p>I really liked doing this project and what a <em>killer</em> voiceover from <a href='http://voice123.com/francissmith1'>Nick Smith</a>.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Throwback Spot</title>
			<link>/work/jersey-mikes-schoolyard</link>
			<guid>/work/jersey-mikes-schoolyard</guid>
			<pubDate>2012-02-13 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
			<author>thekitchen.co</author>
			<description>
				
			</description>
			<content:encoded>
				<p>Last year, we traveled out to Los Angeles and drove about an hour north of the city to the charming town of Ojai (pronounced &#8220;Oh, Hi!&#8221;) to shoot a television spot for <a href='http://jerseymikes.com'>Jersey Mike&#8217;s Subs</a>.</p>

<p>You may not know about Mike&#8217;s if they aren&#8217;t in your area, but over the last several years, they&#8217;ve opened something like 600 stores nationwide.</p>

<p>I had come up with a concept based on a lot of the brand strategy I&#8217;d seen them implementing over the years I worked for <a href='http://scherzi.com'>Scherzi Studios</a>. The concept was to make a spot that harkened back to some of the spots I remember from childhood. <a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ex2DJnvyFsI'>One in particular</a> I remember was for Pizza Hut and really left an impression about Pizza Hut being a kid- and family-friendly place that supports local kids.</p>

<p>Well, that&#8217;s what Jersey Mike&#8217;s message is all about, so on a whim I just scratched out this concept about a magical submarine sandwich that fixes up the playground at a distressed school.</p>

<p>In casting, I was definitely looking for someone a little less whitebread blond and blue eyed, but Taylor was so good that she won handily.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Mitchell Associates Commercial</title>
			<link>/work/mitchell</link>
			<guid>/work/mitchell</guid>
			<pubDate>2011-11-12 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
			<author>thekitchen.co</author>
			<description>
				
			</description>
			<content:encoded>
				<p>We participated in a commercial competition put on by the Delaware Independent Filmmakers and the <a href='http://newarkfilm.com'>Newark Film Festival</a>.</p>

<p>The contest is a pretty interesting concept, as it gives each major sponsor of the festival its own ad, which runs before each screening. The filmmakers who are competing get to put their work on the big screen and stand to win some money, the sponsors get a 30-second spot for themselves, and the festival gets a nice way to plug the sponsors.</p>

<p>Each filmmaker is assigned a client based on a lottery, and I was given <a href='http://mitchellai.com'>Mitchell Associates</a>, a pretty big interior design/architecture firm here in Wilmington.</p>

<p>Mitchell was awesome to work with, and I think we got a pretty nice spot out of this. Only part I&#8217;m dubious about is the voiceover, which is my first ever attempt at recording myself&#8230;</p>

<p>The music was composed and produced in a pinch by the ever-so-talented <a href='http://eluttinger.com'>Elizabeth Luttinger</a> out in Los Angeles.</p>

<p>Also, we won. Not a big deal.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Style Icons with Manuel Schnatter</title>
			<link>/ideas/manuel-schnatter</link>
			<guid>/ideas/manuel-schnatter</guid>
			<pubDate>2011-10-22 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<author>thekitchen.co</author>
			<description>
				
			</description>
			<content:encoded>
				<p>Dan Frigolette and I lived on the same floor freshman year at Syracuse. Since then, he&#8217;s gone on to be a full-time comedian and promoter.</p>

<p>We also both happen to be from the Syracuse area. One day when we were both home visiting family, Dan called me up and asked if we could shoot a quick comedy sketch. We had little in mind other than a character he had been working on named Manuel &#8220;Benny&#8221; Schnatter.</p>

<p>We spent the afternoon together and this is what we made.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>the Kitchen Logo</title>
			<link>/ideas/kitchen-logo</link>
			<guid>/ideas/kitchen-logo</guid>
			<pubDate>2011-10-05 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
			<author>thekitchen.co</author>
			<description>
				
			</description>
			<content:encoded>
				<p>If it&#8217;s true that <a href='http://daringfireball.net/2012/02/walter_isaacson_steve_jobs'>design is how it works</a>, then that&#8217;s the kind of designer I would consider myself. Though I&#8217;ve done quite a bit of visual design in my life, including this site, I&#8217;ve not had much formal training in proper graphic design and typography, so when it came time to create a mark for my new company, I felt I needed to go with <a href='http://twitter.com/bradwason'>a pro</a>. Luckily, Brad Wason, at the time heading 23rd&amp;5th, needed a quick video done for a pro-bono client of his, so I was able to barter my work on that video towards the creation of what would become the logo for the Kitchen.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a damned good thing I hired Brad for the job, because the ideas I was sketching are embarrassing to look back at. Brad was very professional in taking me through a proper questionaire, which I snarled at and ripped up because it made me think about stuff I didn&#8217;t want to think about.</p>

<p>In our first meeting, I said all the vague, generic words that you say (&#8220;I want it to be like super slick and modern, but evoke tradition and the past, and I want it to be clean and timeless, and I want it to be one color but maybe lots of colors&#8230; etc.&#8221;)</p>

<p>Anyways, the experience made me really identify with some of my clients. Sometimes, you really just <em>don&#8217;t know</em> what you want, and often this problem can arise on the projects most important and central to your business. Sometimes you&#8217;re just too close, and this was definitely the case with me and my company&#8217;s oh-so-important mark that will of course go on to be stamped on everything and to live forever as an indelible historic brand.</p>

<p>Brad came back with two versions. One really slick, and the other really friendly. I wanted both slick and friendly, so we made &#8220;a Frankenstein monster&#8221; (as Brad calls it) out of both of them.</p>

<p>Oh. And I love it. I love it so much. It soothes me sometimes just to look at it. This is why, sometimes, you just have to hire a pro.</p>
			</content:encoded>
		</item>
		
		
	</channel>
</rss>